MOHSIN IQBAL

REACT DEVELOPER . 03486869545

· DETAILS ·

03486869545 m.mohsin.iqbal@outlook.com

· LINKS ·

linkedIn

• SKILLS • JavaScript

React

Material Ui Formik

Python

HTML & CSS MySQL

Git

♣ PROFILE

Self-motivated Web Developer with 1.5 yrs of experience in React Js development working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in roles indulging best practices and offering diverse customer projects.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Engineer (React Js) at Big Byte Insights Pakistan, Lahore

August 2020 - Present

- Develop high performance customer facing financial application using ReactJS, Redux-saga, React Hooks, React-Router, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4
- Built custom components for UX-Library consisting Accordion, Filters, Dropdown, Carousel, Button, Checkbox, Input, Icons
- Developed custom API layer to handle all CRUD transactions, JWT token management and implemented interceptors to embed custom headers
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies, including Redux, Redux thunk and redux-saga
- Exclusively used React-Hooks to handle application life-cycle processes
- Used Middleware, Redux-Saga with ImmutableJS in application to retrieve and store data from Back-End and to also perform RESTFUL services
- Effective use of native HTML elements and custom tags to enhance SEO optimization and application ADA compliance feature
- · Expertise usage of GitLab and JIRA as version control and tracking units.
- Worked in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better application

Software Engineer at KICS Lahore

January 2020 — August 2020

- · Python Basic (Lists, Dictionaries, Loops)
- File Handling (Advanced), Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures II Git (working with Pull Requests, Repositories, Tasks assigning)
- · Django websites development from scratch
- · Working in python web scraping team
- · hands on experience with python web scraping framework scrapy and selenium
- API requests sending Post,Get

 Worked on Blockage Avoidance Techniques like Proxies,User Agents etc

 Reverse Engineering to find hidden API's
- · Data Cleaning using Python Pandas library.

EDUCATION

BS(Computer Scence), University of Engineering and Technology Lahore August 2016 — August 2020

★ PROJECTS

Intellistocks.ai

- Intellostocks.ai provides you with the investment research that helps you avoid losses in your portfolio, by keeping you on top of investor activity and sentiment on social media.
- Intellostocks.ai provides you with the investment research that helps you avoid losses in your portfolio, by keeping you on top of investor activity and sentiment on social media.
- · Tech Stack: React & Django
- · Project Link: https://intellistocks.ai/

Lead Generation

- It was a job potals that uses lead generation data to give client flexibility to search jobs around the world in single application.
- Tech Stack: React & Django

Coin Algo

 crypto related dashboard that will show user the different collection stats on <u>Opensea</u>

Project Link: https://coinalgo-develop-dot-webdata-207211.ew.r.appspot.com/

